hello my name is Andrew Van Slaars
and this is a quick walkthrough of how
to configure riot js to work with
webpack. If you're not familiar with riot js
you might want to check out my
previous videos to get you started.
in this video
we're going to cover getting webpack
and the dependencies we will be using
installed via MPN setting up the web a
configuration file process are tagged in
javascript files and serving a page with
our bundled assets through webpack's
development server. let's get our
environment setup. I've created an empty
directory for this project and I have
both atom and terminal window pointed to
that directory so let's get started.
because we're going to be using NPM
modules we're going to start with an MPN in
it and we're going to pass at the white
flag so it takes the default so we don't
have to press enter for each one
and now I'm gonna NPM install webpack
passing it perceived flag now that we're
packs installed and NPM install again at
the saved a flag web pack of service in
order for webpack's process for dot tag
files that were going to use for Ryan
we're gonna install a tackler NPM
install saved as tagged loader
where are they going to install the
battle over again so we're packing
process or javascript files where we may
choose to use yes six her yes 2015
syntax babble order has a couple of
dependencies so I'm p.m. in star Jan C
uses this concept of presets so install
the preset for yes 2015
and of course we want to set up right so
we're gonna NPM install safe right
if we look at packaged
has been installed as a dependency and
web packed with Pakistan server are
loaders are powerful dependencies have
been installed as dead dependencies so
we're ready to get moving then next
thing we're going to want to do is
create our web a configuration file so
in the terminal I just hope that in
touch where pack that config that chess
open that file up and atom and the first
thing we're going to do is we're going
to reference newspass mitral
an asset
exports to equal an object literal and
the first property we're gonna give that
objects as entry and that's gonna tell
web back what file to use as our entry
point so you see here are pointing to
source indexed at Jas and will create
that file once we're done with the
configuration or second properties
output and output as an object and
output has a pet property gonna set to
the current directory name and a
property that we're gonna set to bundle
Jas and this is going to be the file
name would pack outputs with all of our
bundle JavaScript
next we'll create a module
bernie is also going to be an object
and their object is going to take a
lawyer's array and each letter is an
object will start with the Babel order
to create object in the first property
we're going to give it a test and test
is going to take a red X that's kind of
point basically tell us which files to
process so in this case we're gonna want
anything that ends in t.j s second
property is gonna be the loader itself
as we say hey point anything with a.j s
extension and use the battle over on
that but we want to make sure that we're
not trying to process everything in the
note modules directory so we're gonna
pass note modules to the exclusive
property and babble also has a constant
the presets that we saw we were
installing or dependencies so we're
gonna pass a query object query object
is going to take a preset array and
we're going to have that are he has 2015
and now we need to configure the tag
loader so it's going to follow the same
pattern so have a test that's what files
to process this case we use anything
that ends with that tag the letter to
use on those files and that's going to
be our tag loader
and we want to make sure we're not
processing the note modules directory so
I exclude that
we can see
and that pretty much handles our
configuration for the setup now we're
gonna go into package that JSON and
we're gonna set up our scripts so that
we can run the web packed up sir so take
that placeholder test script that they
put in there will remain that death or
glory place the content of that with a
call to web pack that server we can say
that they're gonna create that source
directory that we pointed to in our web
pack configuration and I'm going to
create an index JSP file in there that's
going to be our entry point and in the
root directory I'm also gonna create an
index HTML file and I'm gonna throw a
basic shelves HTML in there and give
that a title
and in the body and then had a script
tag that points to fund all that chaos
and you'll remember that's the output
that we told went back to create our
source files
an accredited tags directory inside the
source folder
this is where we're going to put our
riot tanks so create a new file there
and just for demonstration purposes will
create a sample output will call sample
output as a root element will throw in
h1 in there will say hello again right
jus gotta go back to index HTML and as a
reference to that
now we need to set
he's so we can mount that tag to the
page so in indexed at Jas I'm gonna
create a variable Ryan and I'm gonna
pointed to the riot nude model also
gonna require my tag file a sign that to
a variable because I don't need to
reference said through variable I just
need to make sure that the script is
included on the page when everything
gets bundled together and now added
document that a defenseless player for
the DOM content cohort event just to
make sure my pages been fully loaded in
the car back for that i'm gonna call
right now has a sample output I can say
that back in the terminal I can use that
and p.m. script that I added earlier by
typing in and him run does well we
should see that all run through web pack
in a lit up the web packed app server or
create a bundle and you'll see that it's
processed our index such a ass right Jas
and our sample output that tag and that
we can see this through localhost 8080
and you'll see it's serving our page has
bundle their assets and showing us her
output from Artech not a nice thing
about what pacs dead server is that it
automatically watches for changes in our
files so if I go into the sample output
that tank and I make some changes to
paragraph of Lorem Ipsum here say there
and you'll see that terminal has updated
and I can also go back into my
javascript and because I'm using the
battler I can use yes yes 2015 a terrace
index here and I can see if you will see
that it updates the bundle and if I go
back to the browser and refresh
everything has been updated so we know
it's working thank you for watching hope
you found this helpful and please check
back for future videos